MASAKI KOBAYASHI

https://www.makky.io makky@klis.tsukuba.ac.jp Tsukuba, Japan. Last Update: January 31, 2019

INTEREST

I am a 1st-year Ph.D. student at the Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies, University of Tsukuba. My current research interest is Human-Machine collaboration in Crowdsourcing for efficient microtask processing. Currently, I am studying to propose task assignment algorithms for Human and AI workers satisfying the data quality requirement from requesters.

I am also interested in developing web applications. I worked at 10+ companies/institutes as a part-time engineer/intern. I am exceptionally fluent in JavaScript/TypeScript/Ruby/Python. Proud works are ChainerUI and Crowd4U.

EDUCATION

University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2019 - Present

Ph.D Student,

Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies.

Advisors: Kei Wakabayashi, Hiromi Morita and Atsuyuki Morishima.

University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2017 - March 2019

Master of Informatics,

Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies.

Advisors: Hiromi Morita and Atsuyuki Morishima.

University of Tsukuba, Japan.

April 2013 - March 2017

Bachelor of Library and Information Science,

College of Knowledge and Library Sciences, School of Informatics.

Advisor: Atsuyuki Morishima.

EMPLOYMENT

Research	Assistant	University	of Tsu	kuba, Japan.
----------	-----------	------------	--------	--------------

April 2019 - Present

JST CREST CyborgCrowd Project

Engineer (Part-time) Preferred Networks, Inc.

October 2017 - Present

ChainerUI Team (I published ChainerUI)

Engineer (Part-time) Bit Journey, Inc.

September 2017 - Present

Intern Arm Treasure Data inc.

August 2018 - September 2018

Intern Preferred Networks, Inc. August 2017 - September 2017

Engineer (Part-time) LINE Corporation.

April 2016

Intern CyberAgent inc. September 2015

Intern National Institute of Informatics, Japan.

August 2015

Intern pixiv inc.

March 2015

Engineer (Part-time) 3-shake inc.

July2016 August 2017

Engineer (Part-time) BearTail inc.

May 2014 - March 2015

Engineer (Part-time) Has-key, inc.

August 2013 - March 2017

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant University of Tsukuba, Japan. Database Technology Class

October 2019 - December 2019

Teaching Assistant University of Tsukuba, Japan. Introduction to Data Engineering Class

April 2019 - July 2019

Teaching Assistant University of Tsukuba, Japan. Database Technology Class

October 2018 - December 2018

Teaching Assistant University of Tsukuba, Japan. Introduction to Data Engineering Class

April 2018 - July 2018

PUBLICATIONS (FIRST AUTHOR)

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCES (REFEREED)

1. Kobayashi, M., Morita, H., Matsubara, M., Shimizu, N. and Morishima, A.: An Empirical Study on Short- and Long-term Effects of Self-Correction in Crowdsourced Microtasks. Proc. of the sixth AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing, pp.7987, Zurich, 2018.7.

DOMESTIC CONFERENCES (REFEREED)

2. Masaki Kobayashi, Kei Wakabayashi, Atsuyuki Morishima. Efficient microtask assignment to Human + AI Crowd. WebDB Forum 2019, Japan.

DOMESTIC CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS (NOT REFEREED)

- 3. Kobayashi, M., Morita, H., Matsubara, M., Shimizu, N. and Morishima, A. Analysis of the effect of reference answer presentation on quality improvement of crowd workers. DEIM 2019.
- 4. Kobayashi, M., Morita, H., Matsubara, M., Shimizu, N. and Morishima, A. Short-term and long-term effects of presenting reference answers from others in improving the quality of crowd workers. DEIM 2018.
- 5. Kobayashi, M., Shimizu, N. and Morishima, A. A Self-Correcting Microtask Assignment Method Considering Workers Improvement. DEIM 2017.
- 6. Kobayashi, M., Fushimi, T., Sato, T. Estimation of User Behavior Model Using Purchasing History. DEIM 2016.
- 7. Kobayashi, M., Fushimi, T., Sato, T. Input Support Method Based on Frequent Patterns of Cooking Recipes. In Proceedings of IEICE technical report, 2015.

RESEARCH GRANTS

AIP Challenge Program JST AIP Network Lab, Japan. 1,000,000 JPY

August 2019 - March 2020

AWARDS

- Enterprise award in WebDB Forum 2019 (LIFULL award and FRONTEO award).
- Repayment Exemption for Students with Excellent Grades, JASSO Type 1 scholarship, 1,200,000 JPY, 2019.
- Graduate School of Library, Information and Media Studies Provosts Award, University of Tsukuba, Japan, 2019.
- Student presentation award in DEIM 2017.

- 3rd prize in Git Source Code Contest 2016, HASIGO Inc.
 Title: Developing a WebApp for Checking Graduation Requirements from School Records
- Platinum award, ThinkQuest JAPAN 2013.
 Title: Website to Think about 3.11 Earthquake
- Grand Prize in ICT Challenge+R 2012, Ritsumeikan University, Japan. Title: Book Retrieval System using Google Street View of Original Panorama Images

LINKS

- https://www.makky.io/
- https://github.com/makky3939
- https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=6jE4oTYAAAAJ
- https://speakerdeck.com/makky